[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d03", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Barney Fife?", "answer": "Sheriff Andy Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26d", "question": "What is a nanominute?", "answer": "One-billionth of a minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cb", "question": "Before being sold, to which country did the web suffix \".me\" belong to?", "answer": "Montenegro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e7", "question": "Which rock guitarist did Johnny Depp use as an inspiration for his Jack Sparrow character?", "answer": "Keith Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65b", "question": "The city of St. Louis is located in which state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa8a573838c5c8a417f3f", "question": "How are elements organized on the periodic table?", "answer": "By atomic number - The atomic number corresponds to the number of protons in the nucleus.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e5dffe83fe1f2a824bc6", "question": "Who was \"The Lady Bandit of Arizona\"?", "answer": "Pearl Hart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf0", "question": "Who is Penelope Pussycat's would-be seducer?", "answer": "Pepe Le Pew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596df8ccf0cc2631d16a3c63", "question": "Crazy Horse and Sitting Bull were born in which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338979", "question": "What card game is featured in the novel \"Casino Royale\"?", "answer": "Baccarat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989a8a3cb8751d53e7d75fc", "question": "Who won the fourth Super Bowl?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b03401dd7bf43be5e78c", "question": "What was the Easter Bunny's original name?", "answer": "Osterhase", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd9", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Merchant of Venice\", who was Shylocks wife?", "answer": "Leah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae7", "question": "Who composed the Christmas carol \"Silent Night\"?", "answer": "Franz Xaver Gruber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9a", "question": "In \"The Hunchback of Notre Dame\", what is the name of the gypsy girl who befriends Quasimodo?", "answer": "Esmeralda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a5", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339861", "question": "In Disney's \"Snow White\", what kind of animal heart does the Huntsman give to the Queen in place of Snow White's?", "answer": "A Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f7", "question": "What is the longest running event in a decathlon?", "answer": "1500 meters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b3dc01dd7bf43be5e7b6", "question": "What city created a new beachfront when it hosted the Olympics?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be27", "question": "What is another name for a quaver?", "answer": "An eighth note", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b53101dd7bf43be5e7cc", "question": "What is the name for the process of electing a Pope?", "answer": "Conclave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d2", "question": "In nautical terms, what does \"Bow\" mean?", "answer": "Forward", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a871", "question": "What two Canadian provinces have capitals named for the same person?", "answer": "British Columbia and Saskatchewan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015f7d3fe83fe1f2a824c27", "question": "A young women in the 1920's that behaved and dressed boldly was referred to as what?", "answer": "A flapper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c332", "question": "What was the purpose of the ancient medicinal confection made from the marshmallow plant?", "answer": "To treat irritated mucous membranes and increase the flow of breast milk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6c", "question": "What year did Bangladesh become independent from Pakistan?", "answer": "1971", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c18d", "question": "What is the fourth letter of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Delta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b7b6364247bf200fb875", "question": "What year did Belinda Carlisle release the song \"I Get Weak\"?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339088", "question": "What colour was Moby Dick?", "answer": "White", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a99f", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Nyiragongo\"?", "answer": "The Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab0ec8baab681b09292169", "question": "What is the name of the theme song of the TV show 'CSI: Cyber'?", "answer": "I Can See for Miles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46f", "question": "Which politician is known as Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a2", "question": "What forest was home to Robin Hood?", "answer": "The Sherwood Forest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede30d6ce05a3942286dd0", "question": "Who originally sang \"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer\"?", "answer": "Gene Autry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ee", "question": "What is a N\u00e9v\u00e9?", "answer": "Young, partially compressed snow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cb53bb53d1af658864d7", "question": "In the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", how many drummers are drumming?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3867c73aa70ea0b70ad0", "question": "Which US state gets its name from a made-up word?", "answer": " Idaho (Mining lobbyist George M. Willing told Congress \"Idaho\" was a Native American phrase for \"gem of the mountains\". He made it up.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a387", "question": "What is the capital of Iceland?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d9", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Trans-Europe Express\"?", "answer": "Kraftwerk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d3", "question": "On what holiday did Harry Houdini die in 1926?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afcc", "question": "What fort was built on Garden Key in the Dry Tortugas islands?", "answer": "Fort Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e4", "question": "What was Higgins first name in the TV show \"Magnum PI\"?", "answer": "Jonathan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c089", "question": "Wanamaker's of Philadelphia first US store to install what in 1878?", "answer": "Electric illumination", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4301ff048f679a45ab7f", "question": "What is a hominid?", "answer": "An Upright-Walking Primate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f1648d3f9b80650dbe7f928", "question": "What Disney movie was the song \"Speechless\" featured in?", "answer": "Aladdin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a959", "question": "Which European country replaced the Schilling with the Euro?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60077fd2bd51d85e222ab640", "question": "What was the official diagnosis when van Gogh was hospitalized in 1888?", "answer": "When Van Gogh was hospitalized on Christmas Eve 1888 in Ales, his official diagnosis was \"acute mania with generalised delirium\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338892", "question": "Which side of a book are the odd-numbered pages usually on?", "answer": "The right", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01f", "question": "Which of the two leads of 1995's movie \"Friday\" didn't appear in either of the sequels?", "answer": "Chris Tucker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37e", "question": "The duck-billed platypus is one of only three mammals in the world that can do what?", "answer": "Lay eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a8", "question": "The World's first \"sister cities\" were what Spanish city and its US midwestern namesake?", "answer": "Toledo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e8", "question": "What are the two highest valued letters in Scrabble?", "answer": "Q and Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b10", "question": "In the X-Men comics, what element is fused with Wolverine's bones?", "answer": "Adamantium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f5661433a95c66dc4fe75f", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81b63d0de9af39e9d4678", "question": "Where did the deadliest avalanche occur?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d4", "question": "Who played the role of Macauley Connor in the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff510e2d24dd593ee3eacc7", "question": "What military campaign is colloquially known as the \"Bekaa Valley Turkey Shoot\"?", "answer": "Code-named\u00a0Operation Mole Cricket 19, Israeli aircraft destroyed 82-86 of 100 Syrian aircraft in the 1982 Lebanon War.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d2", "question": "What is the English translation of the area of Cuba called Bahia de Cochinos?", "answer": "Bay of Pigs", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add8", "question": "When did the \"Eighty Years War\" end?", "answer": "1648", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea49d6ff048f679a45abbc", "question": "What part of the plant gets water and nutrients to the rest of the plant?", "answer": "Stem", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964a", "question": "What planet is home to the Jedi Temple?", "answer": "Coruscant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c096", "question": "In what sport do teams compete for the Swaythling Cup?", "answer": "Table tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339966", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the comic book store?", "answer": "The Android's Dungeon and Baseball Card Shop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacf", "question": "What is the study of the Sun called?", "answer": "Heliology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c348", "question": "Who is considered the father of the computer due to his plans for a steam-powered difference engine?", "answer": "Charles Babbage", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba69", "question": "In what year was Gettysburg National Military Park founded?", "answer": "1895", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b4cae662d71a53650ff0", "question": "What literary genre is Edgar Allen Poe credited with starting?", "answer": "Crime novels", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e66306d333868d34d732", "question": "What did Louis Braille invent?", "answer": "A writing system for blind people", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba00", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Honus Wagner play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36f", "question": "James Hunt was disqualified after winning which Grand Prix?", "answer": "1976 British Grand Prix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8aa6b01dd7bf43be5e75a", "question": "What\u2019s another name for a footrest?", "answer": "Ottoman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25e", "question": "What is a wallaby?", "answer": "A kangaroo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d43", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Alien 3\"?", "answer": "Sigourney Weaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37b", "question": "Who conquered the Matterhorn in 1865?", "answer": "Edward Whymper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77d45024f0f7a362efd555", "question": "What song has the lyrics \"I don't ever wanna feel, like I did that day\"?", "answer": "Under the Bridge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6644ea5bfecdd737e0853", "question": "Who was the highest-paid TV host in 2018?", "answer": "Judge Judy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc931c60f0007efaba0e5a", "question": "What is the name of Gene Autry's horse?", "answer": "Champion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ed6206d333868d34d76c", "question": "Which famous European structure was only supposed to stand for twenty years when it was built?", "answer": "Eiffel Tower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdd69e347d002c297e4f0", "question": "What are affected by Phylloxera?", "answer": "Grapevines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fde", "question": "What is the literal translation of the Greek word \"Utopia\"?", "answer": "No-place", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a1e1d75b5a031299b74573b", "question": "The Okapi is native to which African country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067dbfff9c0647b50a8073", "question": "Which gaming franchise celebrated its 20th anniversary on February 27, 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600243b84be4723ccac2219a", "question": "Which semi-autobiographical novel by James Baldwin tells the story of John Grimes, a Harlem teenager in the 1930s?", "answer": "\"Go Tell It on the Mountain\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5921fed8a4edfd43a087add2", "question": "What currency was used in the Netherlands before the introduction of the Euro?", "answer": "Guilders", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf0", "question": "What is the condition resulting from prolonged muscular or mental activity?", "answer": "Fatigue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae6", "question": "How many strikes in a row earns you a perfect game in regular 10\u00ad pin bowling?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a8", "question": "What is the common name for the fluid expelled from the body by the process of lacrimation?", "answer": "Tears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab4", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Ecuador?", "answer": "Andean condor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c0", "question": "What \"Pink Panther\" director produced the TV show \"Peter Gunn\"?", "answer": "Blake Edwards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b805", "question": "In the clothing store name \"L. L. Bean\", what do the letters \"L\" stand for?", "answer": "Leon Leonwood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339272", "question": "What is the real name of the Food Network's chef \"The Barefoot Contessa\"?", "answer": "Ina Garten", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb4", "question": "What 1990's one-hit wonder wrote Christina Aguilera's hit song \"Beautiful\"?", "answer": "Linda Perry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdb47e347d002c297e4db", "question": "Where were the 1956 Summer Olympics held?", "answer": "Melbourne, Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c278", "question": "What is November's birthstone?", "answer": "Topaz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e910215d7247dfc0fa00310", "question": "At what speed do massless particles travel in vacuum?", "answer": "Speed of light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad9dc42e748bb36357acddc", "question": "Which shark has seven gill slits, as opposed to the normal five?", "answer": "The Sevengill shark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a4", "question": "What Michael Keaton film gives mortals a peek into a Handbook for the Recently Deceased?", "answer": "Beetlejuice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b32363fbf195a31e15d73b9", "question": "In which of Coleridge's poems does an albatross appear?", "answer": "Rime of the Ancient Mariner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a34", "question": "What movie western earned Gene Hackman his second acting Oscar?", "answer": "Unforgiven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8d5cec223966ae8f8852", "question": "What is the name of the leader of the gang that often assaulted Andy in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Bogs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008ddf6f4f3bc4a292f8626", "question": "In what city did American colonists dress as Native Americans and dump an entire, expensive tea into the sea", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69fe920565ad31a57c792", "question": "What is the oldest-known epic tale?", "answer": "\"Epic of Gilgamesh\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b3708a1c3f17ccc40c8e15", "question": "Which floor of the Guinness Storehouse houses the Gravity Bar, where tourists can drink a pint of Guinness?", "answer": "Seventh floor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339050", "question": "Which Russian writer composed \"Peter and the Wolf\"?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7be71877e98cb97778960", "question": "What is the coldest sea on Earth?", "answer": "White Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb4697e83c707845b2119", "question": "\"Chicken of the Woods\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Mushroom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c576877e98cb977789af", "question": "What is the least populous country in Africa?", "answer": "Seychelles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada7", "question": "How many years did the \"Great Plague of Milan\" last?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a13", "question": "What was Ralph Kramden's weekly salary as a bus driver on \"The Honeymooners\"?", "answer": "$62", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ed43eccd244b1771b64500f", "question": "When a horse gallops its hooves act as almost four additional what? ", "answer": "Hearts", "category": "Science"}, {"id": "5ffb5b835dad637d903c881b", "question": "What is the most-popular meat served on Christmas in the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Turkey meat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe903d901dd7bf43be5e871", "question": "Which U.S. federal agency provides protection for the federal judiciary?", "answer": "United States Marshals Service", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd0", "question": "What is the first of the four different stroke's swum in swimming's individual medley?", "answer": "Butterfly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173d4a44491cbd7c5a17ad", "question": "Who is widely credited as the first man to reach the South Pole?", "answer": "Roald Amundsen and his crew of Norwegian explorers first reached the South Pole on December 14, 1911.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babf", "question": "What company introduced the first canned ham in the US in 1926?", "answer": "Hormel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac2", "question": "Who first published \"Little Red Riding Hood\"?", "answer": "Charles Perrault", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133932a", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "Martin Scorsese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbf", "question": "Who wrote the short novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7e", "question": "What Sanskrit word do Buddhists use to refer to the endless cycle of birth, death, and rebirth?", "answer": "Samsara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c444", "question": "What causes pollen to stick to bees?", "answer": "An electrostatic charge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c438", "question": "A group of lions is called a what?", "answer": "Pride", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbf", "question": "Tirana is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978a", "question": "What is the name of the bar in the TV show Family Guy that is frequently visited by Peter Griffin and his friends?", "answer": "The Drunken Clam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a266", "question": "Which dance classic did the group \"The Trammps\" bring us?", "answer": "Disco Inferno", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ff", "question": "What was the name of the club in Liverpool made famous for the Beatles early appearances?", "answer": "The Cavern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fa", "question": "Which country were the 1992 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beaf", "question": "How many hole cards is each player dealt in Texas Hold 'Em?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed5", "question": "What talk show opens with the \"Hot Topics\" rundown?", "answer": "The View", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a6", "question": "Who originally designed the Washington Monument?", "answer": "Robert Mills", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ed", "question": "What member of Fleetwood Mac released a 1981 solo hit single titled \"Trouble\"?", "answer": "Lindsey Buckingham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ee839a72b906b34e3cf6", "question": "What number on the Beaufort wind scale corresponds to hurricane force?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c543", "question": "What do goldfish lose if kept in dimly lit or running water?", "answer": "Their color", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59c1ce957bd84c0ea43ad438", "question": "How many stars are there on the New Zealand flag?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42a", "question": "In what country would you see \"whirling dervishes\"?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe73572eec85e375820b24b", "question": "Who said, \"It\u2019s not enough that we do our best; sometimes we have to do what\u2019s required.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d1", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Mekong river?", "answer": "Vietnam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab61", "question": "What city is associated with Alcatraz?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3bc", "question": "Which capital city was once known as Byzantium?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339309", "question": "Which famous actress began her career playing Dorothy in the \"Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Judy Garland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbab", "question": "What game introduced the characters Raiden, Liu Kang, and Sub-Zero?", "answer": "Mortal Kombat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d119564fea7fe947a2228d", "question": "What is in the Red Data List?", "answer": "Threatened Species", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c14", "question": "What weekly TV show was the first one to be assigned a TV-MA rating in the US?", "answer": "South Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b745", "question": "What Biblical name literally means \"the sunny one\"?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e74606d333868d34d73c", "question": "Where in the Bible is the first Messianic Prophecy mentioned?", "answer": "Genesis 3:15", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935b", "question": "Who played the role of Sue Ann Nivens on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Betty White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76861eec85e375820b2a0", "question": "What is the tallest peak in Colorado?", "answer": "Mt. Elbert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be23", "question": "What color M&M was retired to make way for blue M&Ms in 1995?", "answer": "Tan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c82c", "question": "Thomas Edison was \"the Wizard of Menlo Park\" in what US state?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab1071baab681b0929216b", "question": "Mad Shelia is a Chinese action movie that's heavily influenced by which George Miller-directed blockbuster from 2015?", "answer": "Mad Max: Fury Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae866487f28483af1e7fdd3", "question": "What are the names of the original four Ghostbusters?", "answer": "Peter, Ray, Egon, and Winston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fc", "question": "Who got to No. 3 in the UK with the song \"Joe Le Taxi\"?", "answer": "Vanessa Paradis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636aea967692ea851899a1", "question": "On July 4th of what year was the Declaration of Independence adopted?", "answer": "1776", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590088eccf842fa4c4ba968b", "question": "In which Shakespeare play would you find Constable Elbow?", "answer": "Measure for Measure", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339603", "question": "What movie coined the phrase \"In space, no one can hear you scream\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601214f563c99d48cd169ae4", "question": "Which researcher corrected Einstein's theory of a static universe?", "answer": "Edwin Hubble -- He concluded that the universe is actually expanding, something Einstein would admit was his own blunder.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b6", "question": "With which Major League team did Randy Johnson make his 1988 debut?", "answer": "The Montreal Expos", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8a93801dd7bf43be5e74a", "question": "Which animal symbolizes good luck in Europe?", "answer": "Ladybug", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae10", "question": "Which city hosted the 2004 Summer Olympic Games?", "answer": "Athens", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8b8bec223966ae8f883f", "question": "Who does the voice over for Dory from \"Finding Nemo\" and \"Finding Dory\"?", "answer": "Ellen DeGeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008df6cf4f3bc4a292f862a", "question": "What did Zacchaeus do in order to catch a glimpse at Jesus Christ?", "answer": "Zacchaeus climbed a tree so he could have clear view of the Messiah on his way to Jericho.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59f", "question": "What colorful name is often applied to a sequoia?", "answer": "Redwood", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21c", "question": "Traditional Scottish Highland Games feature which event where competitors throw a tapered 19 foot and 6 inch long log?", "answer": "Caber Toss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049903cf93664eb104868d", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Tennessee?", "answer": "Nashville", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a4e212f2a7826b9b8733", "question": "Which Panamanian boxer's nickname, translated into English, means \"Hands of Stone\"?", "answer": "Roberto Duran", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a4a220565ad31a57c7c0", "question": "What are Rocky and Bullwinkle\u2019s full names?", "answer": "Rocket J. Squirrel and Bullwinkle J. Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0af", "question": "Who was Al Gore's running mate in the 2000 presidential election?", "answer": "Joe Lieberman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95e", "question": "At what age does a filly become a mare in thoroughbred horse racing?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f07aff048f679a45aa9d", "question": "Pteromerhanophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Flying", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfe", "question": "On what date did the \"Dennis the Menace\" comic strip debut in newspapers?", "answer": "March 12, 1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a894", "question": "What city is home to the Oriental Pearl Tower?", "answer": "Shanghai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f2", "question": "Who played Mr. Miyagi in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Pat Morita", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75d", "question": "What was the name of Underdog's girlfriend?", "answer": "Polly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdd61900499cffc60b8423a", "question": "Which ancient people first mined and smelted copper?", "answer": "Egyptians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac5", "question": "A triangle with three equal sides is called a what?", "answer": "Equilateral", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f9f5fe83fe1f2a824c35", "question": "Maxwell House coffee is named after what?", "answer": "A Hotel. \"Maxwell House\" was named after its first major customer, the now-defunct Maxwell House Hotel of Nashville, Tennessee.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a8", "question": "What U.S. state gave the world Little Richard, Otis Redding and Gladys Knight?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0d", "question": "What year was comedian Jon Stewart born?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fe", "question": "What is the first foreign country you would reach if you go south of Detroit, Michigan?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf8b", "question": "What's the main feature of a Chong Sang skirt?", "answer": "Split up side", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe769eaeec85e375820b2b4", "question": "Which is the largest of the Spanish Balearic islands?", "answer": "Majorca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde4a4fc6c6b019850c9a73", "question": "What did the first vending machine dispense?", "answer": "Holy Water", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b3", "question": "The Linke Scale is used to measure the blueness of what?", "answer": "The sky", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bb", "question": "What is a league?", "answer": "A unit of length", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cb", "question": "What day did the Battle of the Somme begin?", "answer": "July 1, 1916", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901f", "question": "Rodin's \"The Thinker\" is believed to be a portrait of what Italian poet?", "answer": "Dante", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d1", "question": "What name is given to a triangular or fanlike river?", "answer": "Delta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65d5f1f3c0ead6880d61b", "question": "According to the Bible, how many sons did Jacob have?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b571c0e67df192a942e3370", "question": "What year did Anthony Burgess publish his dystopian novel, \"A Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "1962", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4d", "question": "What popular comedian authored a book titled \"I Am America (And So Can You!)\"?", "answer": "Stephen Colbert", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3c29e4f032c0db195b483", "question": "Who served as chief minister to King Henry VIII of England from 1532 to 1540?", "answer": "Thomas Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c4", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Michigan?", "answer": "Lansing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5f", "question": "Who played Will on the TV show \"Will & Grace\"?", "answer": "Eric McCormack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb6a365ff7d326b622a98", "question": "Who did Perseus turn into stone with Medusa's head?", "answer": "Atlas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9df73e748bb36357acde9", "question": "The city known as Hot Coffee is located in what US state?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c92", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Orbit City?", "answer": "The Jetsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc2", "question": "What accordion-laden type of dancing is the official state dance of Wisconsin?", "answer": "Polka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f467fa5fdd6dd25324e0", "question": "Which band sang \"Mull of Kintyre\"?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e97b06d333868d34d756", "question": "During World War II, what was the purpose of \"Operation Detachment\"?", "answer": "Capture Iwo Jima", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb3380e368446ca7bd6844", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion looking for?", "answer": "Courage\u00a0", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2157531a458464a93c45f", "question": "What is the name given to people who make arrows?", "answer": "Fletcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef60656ce05a3942286e4a", "question": "In what sport do you use the terms \"Chicken Salad\" and \"McTwist\"?", "answer": "Snowboarding", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8a47ec223966ae8f882e", "question": "How long did Red estimate it will take to tunnel one's way through the walls of the prison in the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "600 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b8dc364247bf200fb884", "question": "Whose debut solo album was titled \"I Got Dem Ol' Kozmic Blues Again Mama!\"?", "answer": "Janis Joplin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a920", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Eustis?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f9f492aaf848b908361b87a", "question": "Which legume can be processed to make dynamite?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93b546bd93ce3a4e5f6a2", "question": "What is the study of water called?", "answer": "Hydrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59067fbfff9c0647b50a8087", "question": "Overall, how many medals did US swimmer Michael Phelps win at the 2016 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ffb733a3a814d89068c65", "question": "Who wanted you to \"Shake Your Groove Thing\"?", "answer": "Peaches & Herb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedda6a6ce05a3942286d85", "question": "What is Mr. Bean's actual first name?", "answer": "According to his television shows and movies, Mr. Bean's first name is actually \"Mr.\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febbc8b7e83c707845b214d", "question": "In what round of the NFL draft was quarterback Tom Brady selected in?", "answer": "Brady was the 199th pick in the sixth round of the 2000 NFL draft.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9a", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, what is the value of the letters \"Q\" and \"Z\"?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe25717658e585fda9cfa3a", "question": "What destructive party item was banned in Hollywood on Halloween starting in 2004?", "answer": "Silly String", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70f", "question": "What North American mammal is also known as the prairie wolf or brush wolf?", "answer": "Coyote", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91d", "question": "Which part of the body does the adjective \"renal\" refer to?", "answer": "Kidney", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a40620565ad31a57c7b9", "question": "What is the oldest of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World?", "answer": "Great Pyramid of Giza", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675f432b59efe0e9417e99", "question": "What animal can dig a tunnel 300 feet long in just one night?", "answer": "A mole", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7d", "question": "Which US president ordered the first troops into Vietnam, starting the ground war for the US?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f7fa01dd7bf43be5e83b", "question": "Aichmophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Needles or sharp objects", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c431", "question": "What is a group of dolphins called?", "answer": "A pod or a school", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fd", "question": "What is a sternocleidomastoid?", "answer": "A muscle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfbb", "question": "March, April and May are the only months that have what?", "answer": "Anagrams - Charm, Ripal, Yam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c138", "question": "What is a \"kiwano\" a type of?", "answer": "Fruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be5", "question": "What two kinds of opera do the Arts recognize?", "answer": "Comic and Grand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b1", "question": "What was Aerosmith\u2019s first Top 10 song on the Billboard charts?", "answer": "Dream On", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339714", "question": "Who played the role of Ross on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "David Schwimmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891c", "question": "What are the characters Vladimir and Estragon always waiting for?", "answer": "Godot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab99d1f21a8909e5c332d3e", "question": "What was Harold Lloyd Jenkins' stage name?", "answer": "Conway Twitty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84b", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the malleus?", "answer": "The ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5956444a803c1f1ebcc4a034", "question": "What country singer is a collector of sneakers and has 40 pairs of them on the road with him for his Home Team tour?", "answer": "Thomas Rhett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00f", "question": "What two metal bands are honored on Beavis and Butt-head's usual t-shirts?", "answer": "AC/DC and Metallica", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd094ec223966ae8f88b9", "question": "In the 1998 movie \"The Man in the Iron Mask\", which character dies defending Philippe?", "answer": "D'Artagnan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339924", "question": "Who was the host of TV\u2019s \u201cUnsolved Mysteries\u201d?", "answer": "Robert Stack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e5", "question": "Guitarist Brian May was part of what popular band?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a805", "question": "What is the name of the Canadian territory that shares a land border with Alaska?", "answer": "Yukon Territory", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded197ea2747c8aff16d34", "question": "Vodka and coffee liqueur make what cocktail?", "answer": "Black Russian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda7", "question": "Whose emblem came from a sketch Lamar Hunt drew on a napkin in 1963?", "answer": "The Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb8", "question": "What empire arose in the Peruvian highlands around 1200 AD?", "answer": "The Inca Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a907", "question": "What major river runs through Rome?", "answer": "Tiber", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958a", "question": "What male actor plays the lead role in the 2005 movie \"The Island\"?", "answer": "Ewen McGregor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338939", "question": "What annual celebration is taking place at the start of \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Christmas Eve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b975", "question": "Which Birthsign spans the months of January and February?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfee79616e6c6d4eba4fd", "question": "The Artful Dodger is a character from which novel? ", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b85", "question": "What is the name of the rabbit in the movie \"Bambi\"?", "answer": "Thumper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa4032c73aa70ea0b70b09", "question": "Where is the Mayan Temple of Kukulcan located?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b727", "question": "Christmas Seals are sponsored by what non-profit organization?", "answer": "The Lung Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e9a6cebfabb9c85d8a97b", "question": "What type of food is \"Limburger\"?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c3049076251badbeacf", "question": "Which unique pet did Calvin Coolidge have during his presidency?", "answer": "Raccoon -- Named Rachel, she might be the most well known pet.  She walked around on a leash and was the master of mischief.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa21", "question": "Where is the Guggenheim museum?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ed", "question": "What US state has been led by Orval Faubus and Jim Guy Tucker?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323608bf195a31e15d73b5", "question": "What character was invented to respond to questions from Gold Medal Flour customers?", "answer": "Betty Crocker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339222", "question": "As a child, what did Casper the Friendly Ghost die from?", "answer": "Pneumonia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded12cea2747c8aff16d30", "question": "Who was kidnapped on the night of March 1, 1932?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81f", "question": "What was the first mass produced game to use people as playing pieces?", "answer": "Twister", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8aeed01dd7bf43be5e784", "question": "How long is the hour hand on Big Ben?", "answer": "9 feet", "category": "general"}]